Guide to the New-York Historical Society Building Renovations and Maintenance Records 1938-2017 NYHS-RG 4
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. 1990s Capital Improvement Projects, circa 1984-2001 (bulk 1989-2000); 16.38 Linear feet in 26 document boxes and two drawers of oversize folders
  - Subseries II.B. Construction Phases I-III, 1990-2001; 7.35 Linear feet
    - Phase II: Certificate of Substantial Completion, 2000 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    - Phase II: Change Orders, 1999-2001 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    - Phase II: Construction Contract (2 folders), 1998 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - Phase II: Construction Meeting Minutes (2 folders), 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4-5)
    - Phase II: Department of Cultural Affairs. Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
    - Phase II: Department of Design & Construction. Correspondence to:, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
    - Phase II: Department of Design & Construction. Correspondence from: (3 folders), 1997-2001 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8-10)
    - Phase II: Department of General Services. Construction Contract, 1995, 1999 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
    - Phase II: Domingo Gonzalez Design [Architectural Lighting Design], 1994, 1997, 1999 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
    - Phase II: Landair Project Resources [Owner's Representative], 1998-1999 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
    - Phase II: Monthly Reports (4 folders), 1998 December-1999 November (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4-7)
    - Phase II: Permits, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
    - Phase II: Requisition for Payment No. 1, 1998 December (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9)
    - Phase II: Requisition for Payment No. 4, 1999 May (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Phase II: Requisition for Payment No. 7, 2000 February (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - Phase II: Requisition for Payment No. 8, 2000 April (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - Phase II: Requisition for Payment No. 9, 2000 May (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Phase II: Requisition for Payment No. 10, 2000 October (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - Phase II: Trade Contracts, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - Phase III: Acoustiguide, 2000 August (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - Phase III: American Airlines, 1997 October (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - Phase III: American Express, 1997-1999 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - Phase III: American History Workshop (2 folders), 1997-2001 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6-7)
      Concerns the development and early evaluation of the interpretative installations for the Luce Center.
    - Phase III: Beyer Blinder Belle. Correspondence to:, 1994, 2000 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Phase III: Beyer Blinder Belle. Correspondence from:, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Phase III: Board of Trustees Resolutions, 1995-1999 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Phase III: Bovis Lend Lease [Lehrer McGovern Bovis]. Correspondence to: (2 folders), 1994-2000 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11-12)
    - Phase III: Bovis Lend Lease [Lehrer McGovern Bovis]. Correspondence from: (2 folders), 1997-2001 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Phase III: Budget Information (3 folders), 1994-2001 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3-5)
    - Phase III: Capital Budget [New York City], 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
    - Phase III: Change Orders (2 folders), 1999-2001 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7-8)
    - Phase III: Chermayeff & Geismar, Inc., 1997 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
    - Phase III: City Council Funds, 1995-1999 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
    - Phase III: Collections [for Luce Center], 1992, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
    - Phase III: Computers [Collections Management Software], 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
    - Phase III: Conservation, circa 1997? (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
      Includes an undated statement of the "function and purpose of the Conservation Department."
    - Phase III: Construction Contract [with Department of Design & Construction], 1999 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - Phase III: Construction Management Agreement [with Lehrer McGovern Bovis], 1998-1999 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - Phase III: CRN Log, 2000 March (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
    - Phase III: Crozier Fine Arts [Storage] (2 folders), 1990-1993, 1999 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5-6)
      Includes documents concerning the legal matter Chemical Bank v. LCM-FSW Partnership, et al.
    - Phase III: Department of Business Services, 1999 June (Offsite-box 20, Folder 7)
    - Phase III: Department of Cultural Affairs (2 folders), 1995-1999 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 8-9)
    - Phase III: Department of Design & Construction. Correspondence to: (2 folders), 1999-2001 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 10-11)
    - Phase III: Department of Design & Construction. (2 folders), 1998-2001 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 12-13)
    - Phase III: Design (2 folders), 1994, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Phase III: Exhibits, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
    - Phase III: Henry Luce Study Foundation. Correspondence to:, 1995, 1998-2001 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4)
    - Phase III: Henry Luce Study Foundation. Correspondence from:, 1995, 1997-2001 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 5)
    - Phase III: John Hilberry Museum Consulting, 1997, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
    - Phase III: Insurance Certificates, 2000 March (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
    - Phase III: Interim Reports, 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
    - Phase III: Landair Project Resources (2 folders), 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 9-10)
    - Phase III: Meeting Minutes (2 folders), 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 11-12)
    - Phase III: Monthly Reports (2 folders), 1999 December, 2000 April (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13-14)
    - Phase III: Proposal. Luce Study Center (4 folders), 1995, 1997-1999 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Phase III: Punchlist, 2000 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
    - Phase III: Purchase Orders, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
    - Phase III: Reed Foundation, 2000 May (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
    - Phase III: Requisition for Payment No. 3, 2000 March (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
    - Phase III: Requisition for Payment No. 4, 2000 May (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9)
    - Phase III: Requisition for Payment No. 5, 2000 May (Offsite-box 22, Folder 10)
    - Phase III: Requisition for Payment No. 6, 2001 April (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11)
    - Phase III: Rockefeller Foundation, 1997 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 12)
    - Phase III: Schedule, 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 13)
    - Phase III: Substantial Completion Certificate, 2000 June (Offsite-box 22, Folder 14)
    - Phase III: Trade Contracts, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 15)
    - Phase III: Woo, John [Catalogue Kiosk and Website], 2000 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 16)
    - Additional Files, 1994-1998 (Box -, Folder -)
    - [Phase I] Monthly Reports (3 folders), 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 18-20)
    - Change Orders, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1)
    - Application for Payment #2, 1996 June (Offsite-box 26, Folder 2)
    - Application for Payment #3, 1996 July (Offsite-box 26, Folder 3)
    - Application for Payment #4, 1996 August (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
    - Application for Payment #5, 1996 September (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
    - Application for Payment #6 (2 folders), 1996 October (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6-7)
    - Application for Payment #7 (2 folders), 1996 November-December (Offsite-box 26, Folder 8-9)
    - Application for Payment #8, 1997 January (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
    - Application for Payment #9, 1997 April (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2)
    - Application for Payment #10, 1997 June (Offsite-box 27, Folder 3)
    - Application for Payment #11, 1997 August (Offsite-box 27, Folder 4)
    - Application for Payment #12 (2 folders), 1997 September (Offsite-box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - Application for Payment #13, 1997 December (Offsite-box 27, Folder 7)
    - Requisition for Payment #7 from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973), 1994 November (Offsite-box 27, Folder 8)
    - Requisition for Payment #25 from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973), 1996 September (Offsite-box 27, Folder 9)
    - Requisition for Payment #1 from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973.02), 1997 October (Offsite-box 27, Folder 10)
    - Requisition for Payment #2 from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973.02), 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 11)
    - Requisition for Payment #5 from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973.02), 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 12)
    - Requisition for Payment #11, 1997 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 13)
    - Requisition for Payment #15 from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973.02), 1998 May (Offsite-box 27, Folder 14)
    - Requisition for Payment #Final from Lehrer McGovern Bovis (Project 1973.02), 1998 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 15)
    - Service Billings, 1998 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 16)
    - Payments. Miscellaneous, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 17)
  - Subseries II.C. Architectural Plans, 1989-1994; 4 Linear feet
    The subseries includes drawings related to the 1990s capital projects. The bulk includes drawings made by or for Allan Greenberg, Architect, in 1989-1990 in connection with various completed or anticipated projects, including the Luman Reed Gallery renovation and roof and façade repairs. The subseries also includes 1994 plans from Beyer Blinder Belle concerning roof and facade renovations.
    The subseries is arranged in roughly chronological order and topically.
    Most of this subseries, through the 1990 documents, were found by the processing archivist in 2016 as standalone documents (i.e., not found in files with other, contextual documents such as correspondence). The Beyer Blinder Belle plans of 1994 were transferred to the archives from the Capital Projects Department in 2019.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.0, 1989 May-June (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 1)
      Includes blueline plans of existing conditions on the 1st and 3rd floors, a proposed basement plan, decorative arts storage on the basement and 3rd floors, and 3rd floor renovations and office plans.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.04 (Luman Reed Gallery), 1989 July (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 2)
      Also includes the related 2nd floor proposed plan (project 08905.0).
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.03, 1989 September (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 3)
      Includes bluelines of the plans for the proposed 1st and 2nd floors.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.06, 1989 September (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 4)
      Includes blueline plans of floor plans for the basement through 4th floors.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.02 (Office Renovations), 1989 November (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 5)
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Various Projects, 1990 May 22 (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 6)
      Includes two sets of blueline plans for various projects, including existing plans for the basement through 4th floors (08905.0), proposed plan for the basement coats and offices (08905.10), proposed plan for the 2nd floor North Gallery (08905.14), and Luman Reed gallery plans (08905.04).
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Various Projects, 1990 June 11 (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 7)
      Includes two sets of blueline plans for various projects, including existing plans for the basement through 4th floors and schedules and details (08905.0), proposed plan for the basement coats and offices and 1st floor (08905.10), proposed plan for the 2nd floor North Gallery (08905.14), and Luman Reed gallery plans (08905.04).
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Various Projects (Revised), 1990 June (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 8)
      Includes blueline plans for various projects, most of which are identical to those found in the above folder, but some of which have revisions (projects 08095.0, 08905.10/11, 08905.04, 08905.14).
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Various Projects (Revised), 1990 June (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 9)
      Includes two sets of blueline plans for various projects identical to those found in the above folder (projects 08095.0, 08905.10/11, 08905.04, 08905.14).
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.06 (Roof & Facade Renovation), 1990 September (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 10)
      Includes a set of blueline plans from Allan Greenberg, incorporating plans by Facade Maintenance Design and H.B. Fishman & Co. Includes elevations, roof, gutter, and other details, demolition plan, and schedules.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.06 (Roof & Facade Renovation), 1990 September (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 11)
      Includes a second set of blueline plans, identical to those in the above folder, from Allan Greenberg, incorporating plans by Facade Maintenance Design and H.B. Fishman & Co. Includes elevations, roof, gutter, and other details, demolition plan, and schedules.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. [Project 08905.06] (Facade Renovation), 1989 December (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 12)
      Includes two sets of preliminary drawings by Facade Maintenance Design related to facade and roof renovations; see above folders.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.10 (Gift Store), 1990 June-July (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 13)
      Includes bluelines of plan for the store, including five different schemes and elevations. Also includes photocopy of a design development for library door enframement.
    - Allan Greenberg, Architect. Project 08905.10 (Gift Store), 1990 July 24 (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 14)
      Includes bluelines of the design development drawings for the store.
    - Christina Weppner (Designer), 1990 June (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 15)
      Includes drawings for the plan and elevations of the accounting offices and gift store stockroom.
    - Richard Jansen, Architect, 1990 June-1992 February (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 16)
      Includes bluelines of plans for proposed layouts for the furniture and Print Room on the 3rd floor (1990), proposed layout for an art storage facility (1990), and proposed stairs and ladder replacements to the auditorium control loft (1991) and a temporary auditorium stage extension (1992).
    - [Richard Jansen, Architect?], 1990 October-November (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 17)
      Includes two Mylar drawings: the Charles Gilbert Hines Gallery and the Main Floor Gallery.
    - Beyer Blinder Belle: Roof Restoration Plans, 1994 September (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 19)
      23 sheets: 14 architectural, 2 structural, 4 mechanical/HVAC (3 labeled as "city package" and one noted as the HVAC basement layout plan), 1 plumbing, and two title sheets.
    - Beyer Blinder Belle:Facade Restoration Plans, 1994 September (Drawer 12A-B9, Folder 20)
      9 sheets: 7 architectural (roof, 4 elevations, typical masonry details, door schedule) and 2 title sheets.